Vinay Kumar Gupta 🕡 Featured

OCA Full Stack Java Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Data Structure, Algorithms, Core Java, Junit, Multithreading, Spring Boot, Jenkins, Bitbucket



Current Designation: Full Stack Java Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Current Company: Net Connect Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Ranchi

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Full Stack Java Developer, Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Data Structure, Algorithms, Core Java, Junit, Multithreading, Spring

Boot, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Oracle DB

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

I am Oracle and Java Certified with 5.4 Years Strong Hand Own Experience in DataStructure and Algorithms, OOPS Concepts, Spring Boot, Java 1.8, Scala, Multithreading, JavaScript, AngularJs,

JSON, Junit, Restful web service , Hibernate, Oracle Database SQL/PLSQL.

Experience with Data Structure, Algorithms and Oracle Database SQL/PLSQL.

Basic Knowledge of Scala, GeoJson, jenkins, build tools like Maven.

Good grasp of multithreaded programming, synchronization and memory management.

Certified in (Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer and Oracle Database 11g Administrator).

Excellent coding and Debugging skills.

Working Knowledge in SVN, Basic Linux Command, Apache Tomcat 1.7, JSON, Web services REST.

Strong problem solving skills, data structures and algorithms.

Arcos login and find bugs from log files using Linux Command.

Deploy war files and merge class files into jar using arcos.

Work Experience

Net Connect as Full Stack Java Developer

Jan 2020 to Till Date

Client: BNP PARIBAS INDIA PVT LTD (Mumbai, India)

Role Full Stack Java Developer

Technology Data Structure and Algorithms, Core Java 1.8, Junit, Multithreading, Spring Boot 2.0, Jenkins,

Bitbucket, Oracle DB, Sonar, Rest API, Web Service, Scrum, Agile Methodology.

Project Assigned REFERENTIAL, TRANSCOM [January 2020 - Till Now]

Responsibility 1. TRANSCOM: For the Approving the Loan Amount need Confirmation matching

process, for this a file has to generate for matching the details of client and extract

specific details from file and match with another file which comes from vendor if

matched successful then pass else failed. To complete these scenarios

AutoVerification we use rest api, oracle db, java 1.8, Junit and jdbc template.

2. REFERENTIAL: Creating New Counter party and decrypt file and send it to another todo directory To complete these scenarios we use Multithreading, rest api, oracle db, java 1.8, Junit and jdbc template.

TEKsystems INDIA PVT LTD as Full Stack Java Developer

May 2019 to Jan 2020

Client: HERE TECHNOLOGY Mumbai, India.

Role Full Stack Java Developer

Technology Data Structure and Algorithms, AngularJs 1.8, JavaScript, Core Java 1.8, Spring Boot 2.0,

Maven, Apache Tomcat 1.8, WebService(Rest API), JUnit, PowerMock, GitHub Repository,

GeoJson, Scala, JSON, Agile Methodology, Scrum.

Project Assigned Here Lanes App [May 2019 - December 2019]

Responsibility 1. Frontend: Create icon on top bar to display information admin name hierarchy. Bell

Notification in the top bar whenever a rule gets triggered with counter which consist

of a number of active validations and show in APP as a table format.

2. Frontend and backend (V alidation support in App): Set of validation/violations which would trigger only if changes being done from app (HERE Lanes app). Lane Speed, Height, Width, Vehicle Access offset values are overlapped for a single lane topology,

Filter the Error and Display in UI.

- 3. Validate multiple Rules in App HERE Lanes: This means, if a single topology consist of multiple violations of the same rule code then app should display individual validation entity for each violation. Introduction of Error message field in validation toolbar This would help users to understand the error more clear error with some contextual information related to it.
- 4. HERE Lanes validation tasks Creation: A new workflow create validation tasks for targeted admins with additional filters like Functional class. Rule Code Violation ID.

INNOVA SOLUTIONS PVT LTD as Full Stack Java Developer

Aug 2017 to Apr 2019

Client: TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES (Mumbai, India)

Role Full Stack Java Developer

Technology AngularJs 1.6, Java 1.7, Spring MVC, Apache Tomcat 1.6, SVN, Arcos, WebSphere, Linux,

JUnit, JSON, Hibernate 3.0, Oracle 11g, Data Structure and Algorithms.

Project Assigned ICICI PRUDENTIAL LIFE INSURANCE [January 18 - April 19]

Responsibility 3. Front End (Create New Policy or new Enhancement): Created Different type of policy

for Online User who can buy policy directly (BOL or SOL) through IMobile app or

through Agent for this provide credential to agent with some Discount.

4. Frontend and Backend: Display application Form to fill According to Business Requirement (Single, Married, Widow, Male, Female, Government Rule) and Age Prospective.

5. Scheduler: Created Scheduler to run used crontab to scheduled and merge multiple pdf which was generated on completion of form and payment known as IUW

Scheduler and saved in DB as well as in Day wise format in directory.

6. Investigate Issues : maintain code and Login to Arcos to view the log file . Debug code in local and fixed it, Deploy war files and merge class files into jar, restart the server,

Using SVN get update and commit files or do Integration with team assigned work.

Role Full Stack Java Developer

, Technology Java 1.7, Apache Tomcat 1.6, Struct, html, javascript, SVN, Arcos, Linux, JDBC, Oracle 11g, SQL/PLSQL.

Project Assigned ICICI PRUDENTIAL (AGENT CREATION) [August 17 - january 18]

Responsibility 1. Frontend and backend (A gent Creation Registration Form): Integration Project and

Display application Form to fill According to Business Requirement

(Single, Married, Widow, Male, Female, Government Rule) and Scheduled Agent

Creation Exam conduct exam .

2. Investigate Issue s: maintain code with Login Arcos, review the log file /Debug code in local and fixed it, Create war file, merge Class file with jar and deploy then restart the server

ATOS GLOBAL IT SOLUTIONS AND SERVICES PVT LTD as Associate Java Developer Jun 2015 to Aug 2017

responsibility - development maintanence and support

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computer Science) from Ranchi University in 2012

PG: MCA (Computers) from Pondicherry University in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Certified Oracle Database 11g Administrator

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last U	sed	Experience
Data Structure And Algorithms			
CORE JAVA			
JUNIT			
spring boot			
Jenkins			
Bitbucket, Oracle DB			
Sonar, Rest API			
WEB SERVICE			

Languages Known

Language)	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English					
Hindi					

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time